mapcustomizer.com 2018-10-22

# Privacy Policy | Mapcustomizer.com

What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our blog, website or app?

When creating an account on this site, you have a few options. You may login in with your email address, and create a password unique to this site. In this case, we collect your email address. You may also log in via either Facebook or Google. In either of these cases, we do not collect your Facebook or Google account credentials, but we do get a token from either Facebook or Google, which can be used to identify you as a unique person. In this case, we do not collect any other information, including email address, name, or anything else. This token just allows us to distinguish you from another user on the site. 

If you choose not to log into this site, no personal information is collected. 

When do we collect information?

We only collect personal information when you register or log into your account. If you choose not to do either of these activities, we do not collect any personal information. 

How do we use your information?

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, create a map, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways: 

  * To personalize user's experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested. 
  * To improve our website in order to better serve you. 

How do we protect visitor information?

We store all personal information in a password-protected database. 

Do we use 'cookies'?

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site's or service provider's systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember which maps were created by you. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. 

We use cookies to: 

  * Understand and save user's preferences for future visits. 
  * Keep track of advertisements. 
  * Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third party services that track this information on our behalf. 

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser's Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies. 

If users disable cookies in their browser:

If you disable cookies off, some features will be disabled It will turn off some of the features that make your site experience more efficient and some of our services will not function properly. For instance, you may repeatedly see informational messages that you have dismissed on prior visits to the site. 

With cookies disabled, you will still be able to create maps, but you will not be able to edit or delete them, since there will be no way to connect you to the maps you have created. 

Third Party Disclosure

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information unless we provide you with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others' rights, property, or safety. 

However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. 

Third party links

We do not include or offer third party products or services on our website. 

Google

Google's advertising requirements can be summed up by Google's Advertising Principles. They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users. <https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en>

We use Google AdSense Advertising on our website. 

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy. 

We have implemented the following: 

  * Remarketing with Google AdSense 

We along with third-party vendors, such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions, and other ad service functions as they relate to our website. 

Opting out: Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising initiative opt out page or permanently using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on. 

California Online Privacy Protection Act

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law's reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy. - See more at: <http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf>

According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:

Users can visit our site anonymously 

Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page, or as a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website. 

Our Privacy Policy link includes the word 'Privacy', and can be easily be found on the page specified above. 

Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes: 

  * On our Privacy Policy Page 

Users are able to change their personal information: 

  * By emailing us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#ec8d8f8f839982989fac818d9c8f999f9883818596899ec28f8381). 

How does our site handle do not track signals?

We honor do not track signals and do not track or plant cookies when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place. Please keep in mind that when we are not planting cookies, we cannot link maps to the user that created them, so you will not be able to edit or delete maps that you create when you have DNT enabled. 

If you choose to log in, then we will be able to associate the maps you create with your account, since the action of logging in overrides the passive DNT signal. 

Does our site allow third party behavioral tracking?

It's also important to note that we do not allow third party behavioral tracking. 

COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation's consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children's privacy and safety online. 

We do not specifically market to children under 13. 

Fair Information Practices

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information. 

In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur: 

  * We will notify the users via email: Within 7 business days 
  * We will notify the users via in site notification: Within 7 business days 

We also agree to the individual redress principle, which requires that individuals have a right to pursue legally enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or a government agency to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors. 

CAN SPAM Act

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations. 

We collect your email address in order to identify you as a unique user on the site, and allow you to manage (ie, edit or delete) maps that you have created. 

To be in accordance with CANSPAM we agree to the following: 

> If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can email your request to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#315052525e445f4542715c5041524442455e5c584b54431f525e5c), and we will promptly remove you from _ALL_ correspondence. 

Contacting Us

If you have questions or comments, you can contact me via email: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#502031242239333b103b313534393e377e3e313d35), or by using the [form on my blog](http://kaeding.name/contact/).
